Henry F. Dobyns Papers 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series III: Writings, 1947-2009
  - Subseries 2: Articles, 1948-2004
    - The 1797 Population of the Presidio of Tucson, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Altitude Sorting of Ethnic Groups in the Southwest, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Apache Rights to Gila River Irrigation Water, 1998 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - An Appraisal of Techniques with a New Hemisphere Estimate, 1966 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Band of Gardeners, 1999 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Blunders with Bolsas, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - A Brief History of the Northeastern Pai, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Brief Perspective on a Scholarly Transformation: Widowing the Virgin Land, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Building Stones and Paper: Evidence of Native American Historical Numbers, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Comments on Depopulation of the Central Andes in the Sixteenth Century, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Comments on Schlesier and White: American Indian Action, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Comments on Some Principles of Sociocultural Integration, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Death of a Society, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - The Decline of Mescalero Apache Indian Population from 1873-1913, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Devil’s Claw Domestication: Evidence from Southwestern Indians Fields, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Direct European Immigrant Transmission of Old World Pathogens to Numic Indians during the Nineteenth Century, 1995 (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Disease Transfer at Contact, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - The Dunn-Howland Killings: Additional Insights, 1980 (Box 58, Folder 19)
    - Ethnic Group Land Rights in the Modern State: Three Case Studies, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 20)
    - Ethnohistory and Contemporary United States Social Problems, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 21)
    - Ethnohistory and Human Resources Development, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 22)
    - Excavations West of Prescott, Arizona, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - Fray Pedro Antonio de Arriquibar, Chaplain of the Royal Fort at Tucson, 1959 (Box 58, Folder 24)
    - Historic Havasupai Population Trends, 1989 (Box 58, Folder 25)
    - Indian Extinction in the Middle Santa Cruz River Valley, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 26)
    - Indian Reorganization Act and Federal Withdrawal, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 27)
    - Inter-ethnic Fighting in Arizona, 1994 (Box 58, Folder 28)
    - The Kohatk: Oasis and Akchin Horticulturalists, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 29)
    - Lance Ho! Containment of the Western Apaches by the Royal Spanish Garrison at Tucson, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 30)
    - Military Transculturation of Northern Piman Indians, 1782-1821, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 31)
    - A Mohave Potter’s Experiment, 1959 (Box 58, Folder 32)
    - More Methodological Perspective on Historical Demography, 1989 (Box 58, Folder 33)
    - Native American Publication of Cultural History, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 34)
    - Native American Urbanization and Socio-Economic Integration in the Southwestern United States, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 35)
    - Native Historic Epidemiology in the Greater Southwest, 1989 (Box 58, Folder 36)
    - New Native World: Links between Demographic and Cultural Changes, 1991 (Box 58, Folder 37)
    - The Nine Lives of Cherum, the Pai Tokumhet, 1998 (Box 58, Folder 38)
    - A Note on the Pai Tribes, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 39)
    - On Issues in Treponemal Epidemiology, 1989 (Box 58, Folder 40)
    - On the Economic Anthropology of Postcolonial National Development, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 41)
    - Order Amid Change... Change Amid Order, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 42)
    - The Origin of the Pai Tribes, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 43)
    - Pai Cultural Change, 1999 (Box 58, Folder 44)
    - The Pai Tribes, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 45)
    - Papago Pilgrims on the Town, 1950 (Box 58, Folder 46)
    - A Papago Victory in 1854, 1957 (Box 58, Folder 47)
    - Patterns of Indoamerican Chief Executive Tenure, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 48)
    - Piman Indian Historic Agave Cultivation, 1988 (Box 58, Folder 49)
    - Pioneering Christians among the Perishing Indians of Tucson, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 50)
    - Preparing for Careers in Applied Anthropology, 1980 (Box 58, Folder 51)
    - Puebloan Historic Demographic Trends, 2002 (Box 58, Folder 52)
    - Reformation in the Cotton Fields, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 53)
    - La Situación actual del indígena y “la raza” en el suroeste de los Estatos Unidos, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 54)
    - Sixteenth-Century Tusayan, 1991 (Box 58, Folder 55)
    - Some Spanish Pioneers in Upper Pimeria, 1959 (Box 58, Folder 56)
    - Sonoran Missionaries in 1790, 1959 (Box 58, Folder 57)
    - Spanish-Language Sources for Genealogical Research, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 58)
    - Superhuman Hearing, Superhorses, and Miraculous Maize, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 59)
    - Taking the Witness Stand, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 60)
    - Teodoro Ramirez: Early Citizen of Tucson, 1987 (Box 58, Folder 61)
    - Thematic Changes in Yuman Warfare, 1957 (Box 58, Folder 62)
    - Thirsty Indians: Introduction of Wells among People of an Arid Region, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 63)
    - Topography and Culture: The Case of the Changing Cage, 1957 (Box 58, Folder 64)
    - Trade Centers: The Concept and a Rancherian Culture Area Example, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 65)
    - Trails through Casa Grande, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 66)
    - Tubac: Where some Enemies Rotted, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 67)
    - University of Arizona Indians Ruins, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 68)
    - What are Nixoras?, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 69)
    - Who Killed the Gila?, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 70)
    - “Your Faith has made you Well”, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 71)
  - Subseries 3: Reports, 1950-2006
    This subseries contains reports produced for various institutions and agencies. Boxes 58-60.
    - Anthropological Analysis of Social and Cultural Benefits and Costs for Stream Control Measures: Phase I, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 72)
    - Anthropological Analysis of Social and Cultural Benefits and Costs for Stream Control Measures: Phases II, 1970 (Box 58, Folder 73)
    - Contribution to the Ethnology of Native American Cultural Concerns with Eight Areas in Arizona, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 74)
    - Cultural Affiliation for the Purposes of NAGPRA, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 75)
    - NAGPRA Consultation and the National Park Service, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
    - Nungwu- Uakapi: Southern Pauite Indians Comment on the Intermountain Power Project Intermountain- Adelanto Bipole I Transmission Line, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 4-5)
    - Nuvagantu: Nevada Indians Comment on the Intermountain Power Project, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 6-7)
    - Papagos in the Cotton Fields, 1950 (Box 59, Folder 8-9)
    - Persistence and Power, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 10-14)
    - Persistence and Power, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Piapaxa `uipi (Big River Canyon), 1993 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Piapaxa `uipi (Big River Canyon), 1994 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Puaxant Tuvip: Utah Indians Comment on the Intermountain Power Project, Utah Section Intermountain- Adelanto Bipole I Transmission Line Ethnographic Resources, 1982 (Box 60, Folder 4-5)
    - Traditional Saguaro Harvest in the Tucson Mountain District, Saguaro National Park, 2006 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Tubac Through Four Centuries, 1959 (Box 60, Folder 7-11)
    - Uatah (fields where we plant all the time): Shivwits Southern Paiute Water Use along Tunakwint, the Santa Clara River, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 4: Book Reviews, 1959-2008
    This subseries contains published copies of book reviews written. Boxes 60-61. This subseries contains restrictions on materials in box 61 folder 3.
    - American Indian Ceremonial Dance and The Maru Cult of the Pomo Indians, 1973 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - American Indian Ceremonial Dances, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - American Indian Population Recovery in the Twentieth Century, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Anthropological Analysis of Power Management, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Apache Mothers and Daughters, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - The Aztec Image, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - Brazil’s Developing Northeast: A Study of Regional Planning and Foreign Aid, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - The Cherokees: A Population History, 1991 (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - Culture Change and Shifting Populations in Central Northern Mexico, 1969 (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Cycles of Conquest (American Anthropologist), 1963 (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Cycles of Conquest (Arizona and the West), 1963 (Box 60, Folder 23)
    - Demographic Collapse: Indian Peru, 1520-1620, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Desert Legends: Re-Storying the Sonoran Borderlands, 1996 (Box 60, Folder 25)
    - Economic Anthropology and Development: Essays on Tribal and Peasant Economies, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 26)
    - Economic Development of American Indians and Eskimos 1930 through 1967: A Bibliography, 1971 (Box 60, Folder 27)
    - Ethnohistorical Approaches to the Study of Religion, undated (Box 60, Folder 28)
    - The Fifth World of Forster Bennett, 1973-1974 (Box 60, Folder 29)
    - First Through the Grand Canyon, 1959 (Box 60, Folder 30)
    - Friars, Soldiers, and Reformers, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 31)
    - Havasupai Baskets and their Makers, 1930-1940, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 32)
    - Hernando de Soto and the Indians of Florida, 1995 (Box 60, Folder 33)
    - History of Greenland I, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 34)
    - The Hohokam, 1977 (Box 60, Folder 35)
    - Indian Survival in Colonial Nicaragua, 1988 (Box 60, Folder 36)
    - Indian Survival on the California Frontier, 1989-1990 (Box 60, Folder 37)
    - Indians in American History, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 38)
    - Instituto Indigenista Interamericano volumes, 1970 (Box 60, Folder 39)
    - Irredeemable America, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 40)
    - The Jicarilla Apaches, 1975-1976 (Box 60, Folder 41)
    - Kuyo Chico and The Politics of Reform in Peru, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 42)
    - A Legacy of Change: Historic Human Impact on Vegetation of the Arizona Borderlands, 1991 (Box 60, Folder 43)
    - Legitimacy and Stability in Latin America and Subversion and Social Change in Colombia, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Lord and Peasant in Peru, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Restricted (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Massacre on the Gila, 1988 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Mission of Sorrows, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Mortality Decline and Its Demographic Effects in Latin America, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Mountain Field and Family, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - The Native Population of the Americas in 1492, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - The Navajo Atlas, 1982 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Northern New Spain: A Research Guide, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Numbers from Nowhere, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Papago Indians at Work, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - The People of the Colca Valley, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Perspectives on Historical Demography, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Pueblo en Vilo: Miscrohistoria de San José de Garcia, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - San Miguel: A Mexican Collective Ejido, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Sharing the Desert, 1995 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Shem, Ham and Japheth and An Indian Canaan, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Smoldering Ashes, 2001 (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Social and Economic Change in Modern Peru, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Sorcerer’s Apprentice, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - The Southwestern Journals of Adolph F. Bandelier, 1883-1884, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - The Struggle for Water in Peru, 2003 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Struggle in the Andes, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - The Structure and Growth of Australia’s Aboriginal Population, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Three Approaches, Three Indians- None Realistic, 1982 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Utopianism and Development in Latin America: Two Studies, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Virtuosity and Dabbling in Native American History, 1972-1973 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Voices from Wounded Knee 1973, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - We Shall Live Again, 1986 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Wisconsin Death Trip, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Women versus Men: A Conflict of Navajo Emergence, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 32)
  - Subseries 5: Speeches, 1952-2005
    This subseries contains various speeches. Box 61.
    - Amaranth in Timucua Horticulture, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - An Anthropological view of Latin American Militarism, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 34)
    - Arizona’s Indian Problem, 1955 (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Civilization and Centralization in Peru: A Case Study, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 36)
    - Claims Research, undated (Box 61, Folder 37)
    - Early History of Tucson, 1972 (Box 61, Folder 38)
    - Ethnographic and Archaeological Identification of Walapai Pottery, 1956 (Box 61, Folder 39)
    - Ethnohistory Williamsburg Meeting, 1988 (Box 61, Folder 40)
    - Historic Apache Leadership, 2001 (Box 61, Folder 41)
    - The Historic Demography of Indoamericans, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 42)
    - Historical Indian Agricultural Practices and Traditions, 1993 (Box 61, Folder 43)
    - The Lone Butte Project, 1986 (Box 61, Folder 44)
    - Mammoth in the Swamp (Multinational Corporation in Latin America), 1976 (Box 61, Folder 45)
    - Native American Trade Centers as Contagious Disease Foci, 1989 (Box 61, Folder 46)
    - Northern Piman Indian Clothing Changes, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 47)
    - On “1491”, 2003 (Box 61, Folder 48)
    - The Organizational Principles of Private Higher Education, 1972 (Box 61, Folder 49)
    - An Overview of AmerIndian historic Epidemiology, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 50)
    - Papago Assimilation, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 51)
    - Pathogens and People, 1988 (Box 61, Folder 52)
    - Pima and Maricopa Indian Economic Genius in 1849, 1982 (Box 61, Folder 53)
    - Sixteenth-Century Historical Demography of American Indians, 1992 (Box 61, Folder 54)
    - Tentative Correlations of Arizona Upland Yuman Ceramics, 1956-1957 (Box 61, Folder 55)
    - Tubac, 2002 (Box 61, Folder 56)
    - The Tucson Presidio and the Apaches in 1830, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 57)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 61, Folder 58)
  - Subseries 6: Publicity Files, 1966-2002
    This subseries contains publicity material including reviews of Dobyns’ books and research. Box 61.
    - Articles with mention of Dobyns’ research, 1966-2002, undated (Box 61, Folder 59)
    - From Fire to Flood: Historic Human Destruction of Sonoran Desert Riverine Oasis, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 60)
    - The Ghost Dance of 1889 among the Pai Indians of Northwest Arizona, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 61)
    - Indian Tribal Series, 1971-1973 (Box 61, Folder 62)
    - Native American Historical Demography: A Critical Bibliography, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 63)
    - Peru: A Cultural History, 1977-1978 (Box 61, Folder 64)
    - The Pima-Maricopa, 1990 (Box 61, Folder 65)
    - Spanish Colonial Frontier Research, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 66)
    - Spanish Colonial Tucson: A Demographic History, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 67)
    - Their Number become Thinned, 1983-1986 (Box 61, Folder 68)
    - Wauba Yuma’s People, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 69)
  - Subseries 7: Miscellaneous, 1950-2008
    This subseries contains miscellaneous letters to the editor, translations from Spanish performed by Dobyns and works sent to Dobyns for editing. Boxes 61-62.
    - Casa Grande- Pinal County, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 70)
    - The Last Will and Testament of Fray Pedro Antonio de Arriquibar, Chaplain of the Royal Fort at Tucson, undated (Box 61, Folder 71)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1950-2002 (Box 61, Folder 72)
    - Manuscript ideas, undated (Box 61, Folder 73)
    - Notes, undated (Box 61, Folder 74)
    - Outlines, 1952-1979 (Box 61, Folder 75)
    - Outlines, 1985-1989, undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Outlines- Project Fiesta, undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Research Proposal- Analyzing 18th Century Lifeways in Northwestern Sinaloa and Southwestern Sonora, Mexico for Use by the Juan Bautista de Anza National Historic Trail, 2008 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Research Proposal- Southwest Mission Research Center Bicentennial Program in Ethnohistorical Editing and Speaking for Arizona, 1972-1973 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Research Proposal- Toward a Hemispheric Perspective on Native American Historic Demography, undated (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Translation- Documentos de los años 1773-1780, para la historia de los Yndios Lipanes, 1995 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Translation- A Trip into Arizona, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 7-11)
    - A Trip through Sonora by A. Pinart, undated (Box 62, Folder 12-14)
    - War Poetry, undated (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Works edited by Dobyns, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Works edited by Dobyns, 1989-1999 (Box 62, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Gila River Indian Community Files, 1732-2004
  This series contains material related to the three decades Dr. Dobyns spent as an expert witness and a consultant in water rights litigation for the Gila River Indian Community. This series is divided into 4 subseries. The material is arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 1963-2004
    This subseries contains contains correspondence with lawyers from Cox & Cox, the Gila River Indian Community and other lawyers related to the cases. Boxes 63-64.
    - A-Z, 1974-1999 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Antone, Cecil, 1989, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Cox, Alan J., 1976-1991 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Cox, Alan J., 1993-1998 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Cox, Alfred, 1974-1995 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Cox, Z. Simpson, 1963-1990 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Eschief, Cornelia, 1985, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Fines, L. Anthony, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Fragua, Roella, 1999-2002 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Gookin, T. Allen, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 10-11)
    - Gookin, T. Allen, 1993-1998 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Gookin, T. Allen, 1999-2003 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Hestand, John, 1999-2003 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Kraeger-Rovey, Catherine, 1986-1998 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Lewis, Emily, 1990-1994 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Mariella, Pat, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Massetto, Sandra, 1983-1989 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - McLeod, Roxie, 1984-1985 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Nicklason, Fred, 1985-1993 (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Norris, Diana, 1997-2002 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Strumpf, Gary, 1990-1992 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Sward, Edwin, 1993-1994 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2: Reports, 1974-2002
    This subseries contains manuscripts written for use by Cox & Cox and the Gila River Indian Community. This includes copies of confidential reports later published by Dobyns. Drafts edited for publication can be located in Series III: Writings. Also included are Dobyns’ comments on expert opinions and other aspects of the case. Boxes 64-70.
    - Allotment in United States Policy toward its First Nations, 1998 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Alluvial Springs in Piman Irrigation, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - An Analysis of Comparative Military Power on the Eastern Sonoran Desert in Arizona Territory from 1848 until 1890, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Ancestors of the Arizona O’odham, 1989, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Apache Chiefs: An Analysis of Southern Athapascan Leadership, 2001 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - “Apache” Treaty: An analysis of the 11 July 1852 Chihenne Chiricahua Treaty of Acoma Pueblo, 2000 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Chronology of a Decade’s Litigation Hearing, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Comments on Arizona Department of Water Resources Fort McDowell Indian Community Water Rights Settlement Prehistory and History, 1993 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Comments on Briefing Report on HSR Investigations of Globe- Equity 59 Rights, 1993 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Comments on Gila River Indian Community Master Plan Report for Land and Water Use, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Comments on Gila River Pima Maricopa Indian Reservation, 1986 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Comments on Hydrographic Survey Report for the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Comments on Motion for Partial Summary Judgment Re Preclusive Effect of Buckeye-Arlington Agreements- W1-203, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Comments on Motion for Partial Summary Judgment Re Preclusive Effect of Haggard Decree- W1-203, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Comments on Motion for Partial Summary Judgment by San Carlos Irrigation and Drainage District- W1-203, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Comments on Motion for Summary Judgment by ASARCO Incorporated- W1-203, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Comments on Rebuttal Disclosure Statement of GRIC and Silas Kisto regarding the Impact of Prior Decrees or Agreements on the Water Rights of the GRIR, 1998 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Comments on A Report to the Committee on Appropriations US House of Rep. on the Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission US Department of the Interior, Jan., 1985 (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Comments on San Carlos Apache Tribe’s Separate Statement of Facts in Support of Motions, 2001 (Box 64, Folder 22-23)
    - Comments on Separate Statement of Facts in Support of Motion for Partial Summary Judgment Re Preclusive Effect of 1907 Sacaton Agreement- W1-203, 1999-2000 (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - Comments on Separate Statement of Facts in Support of Motion for Partial Summary Judgment Re Preclusive Effect of Haggard Decree- W1-203, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - A Comparative Analysis of Plaintiffs’ and Defendant’s Requested Findings of Fact, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - Confidential draft to Gila River Indian Community Water Settlement Negotiating Team, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - Congress Frustrates would-be Gila River Indian Reservation Land Thieves, 1998 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Creating Commercial Extra-Long Staple Cotton by Exploiting Gila River Indian Reservation Natural and Human Resources, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 29-30)
    - Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1997 (Box 64, Folder 32)
    - Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1998 (Box 65, Folder 1-7)
    - Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1999 (Box 65, Folder 8-9)
    - Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 2000 (Box 65, Folder 10-11)
    - An Ethnohistorical Perspective on non-insulin Dependent Diabetes Mellitus (NIDDM) among the O’odham and Peeposh Peoples, 2000 (Box 65, Folder 12-14)
    - Evaluation of Gila River Adjudication Pomerene Water Users Association Expert Witness Report by Shelley C. Dudley, 1994 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Facts and Purposes, 1998 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Facts and Purposes, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Federal Trustee’s Failure to Account for an Electrical Power Transmission line across Gila River Indian Reservation, 1991 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Federal Trustee’s Mismanagement of Reimbursable loan to Gila River Indian Reservation’s Business Committee for Doubling Sacaton Cotton Gin Capacity, 1991 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Floods and Droughts: A Bibliography and Research Guide, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 4-7)
    - From Affluence to Poverty, 1985-1986 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Gila River Indian Community and the United States of America, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Gila River Pima- Maricopa Responses to Historic Economic Opportunity and Disincentives, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Gila River Valley Irrigation: A History of Differential Water Control and Economic Success, 1848-1990, 1991 (Box 66, Folder 11-12)
    - Gila River Valley Irrigation: A History of Differential Water Control and Economic Success, 1848-1990, 1993 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Gileños- Land Valuation, undated (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Globe Equity 59: A History of the Case from 1925 Complaint to 1935 Gila River Decree, 1999 (Box 66, Folder 15-16)
    - Globe Equity 59: A History of the Case from 1925 Complaint to 1935 Gila River Decree, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 1-2)